<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ossohelpsource>
  <folder>
    <title>Other Maemo Weather</title>
    <topic>
      <topictitle>Introduzione</topictitle>
      <context contextUID="help_omweather_intro"/>
      <para>Benvenuti a Other Maemo Weather.</para>
      <para>Other Maemo Weather (OMWeather) è un applet meteo per Nokia Internet Tablets. Esso può essere utilizzato per:</para>
      <list>
        <listitem>Check detailed weather forecast for up to 5 days</listitem>
        <listitem>Update weather information automatically from the Internet (Data provided by xoap.weather.com)</listitem>
        <listitem>Configure nearest weather station automatically using GPS</listitem>
        <listitem>Facilmente personalizzato per selezionare stazione meteo ordinati dal menu a discesa</listitem>
        <listitem>Vedere l'alba e il tramonto volte selezionato per stazioni meteorologiche</listitem>
        <listitem>See current phase of the moon</listitem>
        <listitem>Selezionare tra le diverse dimensioni icona, icona fissa, i colori e la modalità di visualizzazione</listitem>
        <listitem>Vedere alcune caramelle con occhio trasparenza opzione</listitem>
       </list>
      <para>Utilizzare il <ref refid="help_omweather_" refdoc="index"/> di usare le varie sezioni di questo documento di aiuto.</para>
    </topic>
    <topic>
      <topictitle>Come iniziare</topictitle>
      <context contextUID="help_omweather_getstarted"/>
      <para>To activate OMWeather select <display_text>Home</display_text> <display_text>Select applets...</display_text> <display_text>OMWeather</display_text>.</para>
      <para>First thing to do is select the position of a OMWeather applet in home view. You can change applets position simply touching it and dragging it where you want it. Appearance of the applet can be changed from the <display_text>Tool</display_text> icon in OMWeathers weather window or selecting <display_text>Home</display_text> <display_text>Applet settings</display_text> <display_text>OMWeather settings</display_text>.</para>
      <para>OMWeather will use Tablets Home city selection as a default location for weather data. Location can be changed from the <display_text>Stations</display_text> tab in OMWeathers settings window.</para>
      <para>Più informazioni di come cambiare l'aspetto delle applet e di aggiungere, eliminare e rinominare le località possono essere trovate sul <ref refid="help_omweather_settings" refdoc="Impostazioni"/> pagina.</para>
    </topic>
    <topic>
      <topictitle>Impostazioni</topictitle>
      <context contextUID="help_omweather_settings"/>
      <para>The <display_text>Settings</display_text> dialog (accessible from the desktop applet or home views Applet settings menu) provides access to the configurable options that controls how OMWeather appears and run. In addition to the tabs, there are also four buttons. Left arrow will take you to weather view, ok button saves settings, question mark opens help and x button closes settings window.</para>
      <para><display_text>Sations</display_text> tab lists all locations which weather data OMWeather will receive when applets refresh button is touched or automatic update happens.</para>
      <para><display_text>Interface</display_text> tab is used to configure settings that controls visual appearance of the OMWeather.</para>
      <para><display_text>Units</display_text> tab is used to select temperature, distance, wind speed and pressure units shown on weather data. Necessary units can be selected by clicking on corresponding check button.</para>
      <para><display_text>Update</display_text> scheda viene utilizzata per configurare l'aggiornamento di un intervallo di dati meteo. Questa scheda mostra anche il tempo quando prossimo aggiornamento sarà fatto.</para>
      <para><display_text>Sensor</display_text> tab is used control if temperature from the internal sensor is shown on the applet.</para>
    </topic>
    <topic>
      <topictitle>Aggiungi Station</topictitle>
      <context contextUID="help_omweather_add_station"/>
      <para>In questa finestra è necessario selezionare prima un paese da un menu a discesa. Dopodiché è necessario selezionare corretto stato o la provincia (solo in alcuni paesi) e di un posto meteo che si desidera monitorare.</para>
      <para>Aggiungi <display_text>Station Custom</display_text> pulsante viene utilizzato per aggiungere stazioni meteorologiche non trovato sul menu a discesa.</para>
    </topic>
    <topic>
      <topictitle>Aggiungi personalizzato stazione</topictitle>
      <context contextUID="help_omweather_add_custom_station"/>
      <para>Questa finestra dovete inserire il nome e la stazione stazione codice personalizzato per una stazione meteo. Stazione codici possono essere trovati da (http://xoap.weather.com/search/search?here=station_name) o si può usare per CAP US stazioni.</para>
    </topic>
    <topic>
      <topictitle>Settings. Stations tab</topictitle>
      <context contextUID="help_omweather_settings_stations"/>
	<para><display_text>Arrange</display_text> section allows you to remove or rename stations in the list. <display_text>Up</display_text> and <display_text>down</display_text> arrows allows you to change the order of the selected locations.</para>
      <para><display_text>Add</display_text> section allows you to add new weather stations, which will then be listed in the left view.</para>
      <para><display_text>Enable GPS:</display_text> check box is used to enable automatic weather station selection when GPS is enabled.</para>
    </topic>
    <topic>
      <topictitle>Settings. Visuals tab</topictitle>
      <context contextUID="help_omweather_settings_visuals"/>
      <para><display_text>Interface</display_text> tab is used to configure settings that controls visual appearance of the OMWeather.</para>
      <para><display_text>Visible items:</display_text> selects how many icons will be shown in the tablets home screen.</para>
      <para><display_text>Layout:</display_text> selects how icons are shown on the home screen. Possible selections are one row, one column, two rows, two columns or combination.</para>
      <para><display_text>Icon set:</display_text> selects which icon set is used. You can install more icon sets with the application manager (if Maemo extras repository is configured) or going to OMWeathers Maemo garage page (http://omweather.garage.maemo.org/) and downloading icon sets directly from there.</para>
      <para><display_text>Icon size:</display_text> defines icon size.</para>
      <para><display_text> Swap hi/bassa temperatura:</display_text> selezione cambierà modo come la temperatura più alta e la più bassa per un giorno è mostrato sulla applet. Se è selezionata, verranno visualizzati applet ad alta temperatura prima.</para>
      <para><display_text>Show wind:</display_text> selection will show wind on the applet.</para>
      <para><display_text>Current weather on first icon:</display_text> selection will show current weather on first icon and forecast for a rest of the day is shown on the next icon.</para>
      <para><display_text>Hide station name:</display_text> selection will control if station names are shown on the applet.</para>
      <para><display_text>Hide arrows:</display_text> selection will control if arrows used to change weather station are shown on the applet.</para>
      <para><display_text>Transparency:</display_text> selection will show background image behind the icons.</para>
      <para><display_text>Font:</display_text> defines font and it's size used on the applet.</para>
      <para><display_text>Font color:</display_text> defines applets font color. Touching color button will open <display_text>Pick a Color</display_text> dialog where it's possible to select font color.</para>
      <para><display_text>Background color:</display_text> setting defines the background color used for icons. Background color is not selectable if transparency is used.</para>
    </topic>
    <topic>
      <topictitle>Settings. Display tab</topictitle>
      <context contextUID="help_omweather_settings_display"/>
    </topic>
    <topic>
      <topictitle>Settings. Units tab</topictitle>
      <context contextUID="help_omweather_settings_units"/>
      <para><display_text>Units</display_text> tab is used to select temperature, distance, wind speed and pressure units shown on weather data. Necessary units can be selected by clicking on corresponding check button.</para>
    </topic>
    <topic>
      <topictitle>Settings. Update tab</topictitle>
      <context contextUID="help_omweather_settings_update"/>
      <para><display_text>Update</display_text> scheda viene utilizzata per configurare l'aggiornamento di un intervallo di dati meteo. Questa scheda mostra anche il tempo quando prossimo aggiornamento sarà fatto.</para>
      <para><display_text>Automatically updating data when connecting to the Internet: </display_text> selection controls automatic weather data update when Internet connection is established.</para>
      <para><display_text>Switch per la prossima stazione dopo:</display_text> menu a discesa controlli tempo dopo applet modifiche alla prossima stazione meteo.</para>
      <para>Valido per tempo meteorologiche correnti e intervallo di aggiornamento può essere selezionato da un menu a discesa.</para>
    </topic>
    <topic>
      <topictitle>Settings. Sensor tab</topictitle>
      <context contextUID="help_omweather_settings_sensor"/>
      <para><display_text>Sensor</display_text> tab is used control if temperature from the internal sensor is shown on the applet.</para>
      <para>When <display_text>Use device temperature sensor</display_text> check box is enabled, applet will show temperature of the build in temperature sensor. Temperature can be shown after station name or on the new icon. Sensor read interwall can be set to user defined value.</para>
    </topic>
    <topic>
      <topictitle>Desktop utilizzando applet</topictitle>
      <context contextUID="help_omweather_usingdesktopapplet"/>
      <para>Touching icon of a day brings up a window where you can see current weather or detailed forecast for a selected day. On the <display_text>Now</display_text> tab you can see current weather and phase of the moon. <display_text>Day</display_text> tabs will show weather forecast and sunrise/sunset times for a selected days.</para>
      <para><display_text>Tool</display_text> button will open OMWeather settings dialog. <display_text>Refresh</display_text> button will update weather data, <display_text>Question mark</display_text> will open OMWeather info and <display_text>X</display_text> button closes weather dialog.</para>
    </topic>
    <topic>
      <topictitle>Chi OMWeather</topictitle>
      <context contextUID="help_omweather_about"/>
      <para>Attuale Versione: 0.21</para>
      <para>OMWeather è stato sviluppato da Vlad Vasiliev (vlad@gas.by).</para>
      <para>Copyright © 2006-2008 Vlad Vasiliev, Pavel Fialko.</para>
      <para>Meteo dati forniti da: xoap.weather.com</para>
      <para>This program is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either version 2 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.</para>
      <para>This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. See the GNU General Public License for more details.</para>
      <para>You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License along with this program. If not, see: http://www.gnu.org/licenses</para>
    </topic>
  </folder>
</ossohelpsource>